Anderson Tsai

Phone: (909)-539-7599

Email: andersontsai87@gmail.com

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/andersontsai

Github: https://github.com/anderson-tsai

Website: https://anderson-tsai.github.io/

Key skills

Python

Java

HTML

PHP

Scheme

Databases

Leadership

Communication

Summary

Berkeley student skilled at technical leadership, communication and presentations. Experienced in full project life cycle from design to implementation to integration. Multi-faceted and knowledgeable in Python, Java, and MySQL.

Projects

May 2020 - Gitlet

Built a minature version of Git. Features full-fledged version-control commands. Created for CS61B Data Structures class at University of California, Berkeley. (https://github.com/anderson-tsai/Gitlet)

Experience

June 2019 - Present Software Engineer Intern | Skoruz Technologies

- Used Python and Java to automate change data capture (CDC) between various data sources (Hive, mySQL, msSQL, MariaDB, Oracle) while leveraging data analytics tools such as Apache Nifi and Apache Kylo.
- Used Python to create adaptive optical character recognition software that picks up tax information from an invoice and used HTML and PHP to create a graphical user interface. (produced for Kotak Mahindra Bank)

Key Achievement:

 Created entirely open-source solution to automate CDC instead of relying on enterprise solutions.

June 2019 – August 2019 Project Management Intern | GBC International Bank

 Helped facilitate a team of five others to create workflows that automate the processing of documents and streamlines the process for other employees at the bank. Created a foundation for workflow automation and established the effective uses of the workflow program. Integrated workflows for the first time at this bank.

Key Achievement:

Bank processes became more efficient on average after implementation.

Education

2019-2023 University of California, Berkeley

BA, Computer Science

Relevant coursework:

- Structure and Interpretation of Computer Programs
- Designing Information Devices and Systems
- Data Structures

Achievements

May 2019 Cal Poly Pomona High School Programming Competition

 Participated in programming competition with hundreds of other competitors (event sponsored by Northrop Grumman, National Security Agency, Snapchat, and Google) and placed within the high school division.